A Guide to the David Rockefeller papers, Photographic collections, Numbered Albums FA1316
Rockefeller Archive Center
- China Trip, 1973, Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 301)
  DR and PR trip to China on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Visit included Hong Kong, Beijing, the Forbidden City. DR met with Zhou Enlai, first premier of the People's Republic of China. He also spoke at an event with Francis Stankard of the Bank.
  149 images.
- Venezuela and Peru Trip, 1997, The album is fragile and coming apart. (Box 302)
  DR trip to Venezuela and Peru with grandchildren. DR's friends Gustavo and Patricia Cisneros joined them. They visited rainforests and Angel Falls in Venezuela and Machu Picchu in Peru. Images of landscape, ruins, and botanicals.
- Birthday Album of Letters from the DR Center for Latin American Studies, Harvard University, 2005 June (Box 303)
  An elegantly bound volume of printed letters to DR on the occasion of his 90th birthday from the faculty, staff, students, and fellows of the David Rockefeller Center for Latin American Studies at Harvard University. No photographs.
- The Blaze, Historic Hudson Valley Event Album, 2015 October (Box 304)
  DR and staff attend The Great Jack-o-Lantern Blaze, an autumn event sponsored each year by Historic Hudson Valley at the Van Cortlandt Manor property in Croton, New York. Included a 100th birthday pumpkin to mark DR's milestone.
- To Dads from Neva: Album of Shared Memories, 1964; 2015-2016; One black-and-white image. (Box 305)
  Scope and Contents Note
  Album of photos with or by Neva R. Goodwin that she compiled as a gift to her father. Mostly images of her family members in Maine in 2015.
- Engagement Photos of David Rockefeller and Peggy McGrath and of Laurance Rockefeller and Mary French, 1934, 1940; Black-and-white images. (Box 306)
  Still photos in frames of the images used as engagement photographs by the two brothers and their brides: LSR and MFR in 1934, DR and PR in 1940.
  4 images.
- Compilation Album of Photos in David's Den, 2005 June (Box 307)
  This album was compiled in 2005 for David Rockefeller by his family to celebrate his 90th birthday. The snapshots show the framed family photographs that hung in David's den at Hudson Pines, his home in Pocantico Hills, New York. The various images include DR with his parents, siblings, wife, children, and grandfather from 1915 to approximately 2000.
  Material related to living members of the Rockefeller family is closed.
- Book on Salon Mexicano (Mexico Room), Center for Inter-American Relations, 1969 (Box 308)
  Elegant picture book of the Manhattan headquarters of the Center for Inter-American Relations (now Americas Society) on Park Avenue. Given as a gift to DR from Carlos Espinosa Inglesias in gratitude for his leadership and support of the center. DR cofounded the center, and his support helped to furnish the Salon Mexicano. This is a printed book, not a photo album. Captions are in Spanish.
- Morocco Trip, Part 2, 1972, Black-and-white images. (Box 309)
  DR and PR trip to Morocco. Images by Joseph Reed. Photos mostly of residents and communities in Morocco, plus a camel ride and sightseeing.
- East Africa Trip, 2003 (Box 310)
  This album is a duplicate of the album in Box 112, entitled "Kenya, Tanzania, Rwanda, 2003." Please refer to Box 112 for the digital image files and further description.
- Carriage Rides Album, 1987 (Box 311)
  Album of carriage rides. DR and PR do not appear in these images, nor are the locations specified. May be from two different events, one of which was in 1987.
  12 images.
- David Rockefeller Visits with Duri, 2000 (Box 312)
  Album of snapshots with DR attending outdoor event honoring Duri (no last name given). Location not specified. Date is approximate.
- Peru Trip, 2012, 2012 February; Some black-and-white images. (Box 313)
  Album of photos printed on boards of family trip to Peru. Images taken by several family members. They visited Iquitos, El Durado, Nauta, Pucate, Symiria, and Waysi. Images of landscapes, indiginous animals and plants, area residents, and DR's family members.
- India Trip, 2011, Some black-and-white images. (Box 314)
  Album of photos printed onto boards of family trip to India. Images taken by several family members. The trip started with a short stay in Paris, and then they visited Delhi, Agra, Jaipur, Udaipur, and Jodhpur. Images of architectural sites, landscapes, area residents, indiginous animals and plants, and DR's family members and staff.
- Hudson Pines and 146 East 65th Street, Album by Ezra Stoller, 1972; Some black-and-white images. (Box 315)
  Printed album of formal photographs taken by Ezra Stoller of David Rockefeller's homes: Hudson Pines in Pocantico Hills, New York, and 146 East 65th Street in Manhattan. Images of interiors and exteriors, plus the surrounding property at Hudson Pines. Esto Photographics retains the rights to these images.
- International Advisory Committee Trip to Brazil, 1976, 1976 May; Black-and-white images. (Box 316)
  DR and PR trip to Brazil on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank's International Advisory Committee. Photos taken by Joseph Reed. They traveled to Rio de Janiero and Brasilia. DR met with several Chase employees in those cities, as well as Mario Henrique Simonsen, the Brazilian Minister of Finance.
  After the trip, they flew to their home in the Caribbean on St. Bart's, called Colombier, which is shown in the last few images in this album.
- David Rockefeller Early Years Album, 1917-1923; Black-and-white images. Original album is fragile: the cover and binding are coming apart. (Box 317)
  Images of DR from his youth, including with his family at their various homes and on trips.
  Restricted due to preservation concerns. Album is fragile and cover is coming apart. Permission required to access original album.
- David Rockefeller Childhood Photos and Photos with Family, 1915-1926; Black-and-white images.; Some photos are poor quality, blurry, faded, washed out. (Box 318)
  Compilation of DR photos from infancy to adolencence. Group photos with his mother, siblings, and pets--although not with his father, John D. Jr. One drawing of DR. Locations include the grounds at Kykuit and Abeyton Lodge (Pocantico Hills), the gardens and the grounds near the Eyrie (Maine), and the house at 10 W. 54th Street in Manhattan. Image 255 is of John D. Rockefeller, Sr., visiting the Richmond Hill, New York, house very late in life.
  298 images.
- Morocco Trip Album ("Travels with Peggy and David"), 1970s; Several images are grainy/faded. (Box 319)
  Oversized album of DR and PR trip to Morocco. Images of local people, markets, and animals. DR is in only one image, and PR is not in any. Original album is labeled as "Travels with Peggy and David."
- World Trip, 1976, Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 320)
  DR trip to Marshall Islands, Guam, Philippines, Hong Kong, Singapore, Indonesia, and Malaysia on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Images by Joseph Reed.
  53 images.
- Africa Trip, 1971, Black-and-white images. (Box 321)
  DR trip to Africa, mostly Nigeria, with images taken by Joseph Reed. DR met with Nigerian leader Ado Bayero.
- Middle East Trip, 1979, 1979 January; Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 322)
  DR trip to Egypt and Oman on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Images by Joseph Reed.
- World Trip, 1971, Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 323)
  DR and PR trip to Egypt, Jordan, Israel, Nepal, Indonesia, Australia, and Bora Bora on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Images by Joseph Reed. In Jordan, DR met with Prince Hassan bin Talal and Prime Minister Wasfi al-Tal, who was assassinated later that year. In Indonesia, DR likely met with Sultan Hamengkuwono IX. A few images of the construction of the Opera House in Sydney, Australia. A few images are in Waimea, Hawaii, at the end of the trip.
  189 images.
- Middle East Trip, 1974, 1974 January; Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 324)
  DR trip to several Middle East countries, including Jordan, Oman, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, and Egypt. They also stopped beforehand in Switzerland and Italy. Images by Joseph Reed. In Italy, DR met with banker Rodolfo Rinaldi. In Oman, he met with Sultan Qaboos bin Said al Said. In Bahrain, he met with Isa bin Salman al Khalifa, its first emir. In Egypt, he met with President Anwar Sadat.
- Mexico Trip, 1972, Black-and-white images. (Box 325)
  DR trip to Mexico, likely on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Images taken by Joseph Reed. DR met with Carlos Hank Gonzalez, a Mexican political leader.
- Family Photo Album, Book I, 1990 (Box 326)
  Compilation album for DR put together by his family members of a family gathering at the JY Ranch in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, possibly to celebrate DR and PR's 50th wedding anniversary. Labeled as "Special Memories Book I."
  204 images.
- Family Photo Album, Book II, 1990 (Box 327)
  Compilation album for DR put together by his family members of a family gathering at the JY Ranch in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, possibly to celebrate DR and PR's 50th wedding anniversary. Labeled as "Special Memories Book II."
  206 images.
- Family Photo Album, Book III, 1990 (Box 328)
  Compilation album for DR put together by his family members of a family gathering at the JY Ranch in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, possibly to celebrate DR and PR's 50th wedding anniversary. Labeled as "Special Memories Book III."
- Family Vacation (untitled), 1993, 1993 July (Box 329)
  DR and PR vacation with family members in Jackson Hole, Wyoming.
- Middle East Album, March 1977, 1977 March; Black-and-white images. (Box 330)
  Album of residents and sites in an unidentified Middle Eastern country, although it is possibly Tunisia or Egypt. Images taken by Joseph Reed and are a subset of those in the album titled "Middle East Trip, January 1977." DR is not in any of these images.
  18 images
- Morocco Trip, Part 1, 1972, Black-and-white images. (Box 331)
  DR and PR trip to Morocco. Images by Joseph Reed. Photos of people, neighborhoods, markets, desert, dance performance.
  86 images.
- Album of David Rockefeller's 90th Birthday Celebration at the Playhouse, 2005 June; Some black-and-white contact sheets. (Box 332)
  Bound album of printed contact sheets from the formal celebration of DR's 90th birthday. Held at the Playhouse on the Kykuit estate property in Pocantico Hills, New York. Attended by family members and friends. Images of the rooms, the decorations, and the attendees.
  Material related to living Rockefeller family members is restricted.
- Morocco Trip, 1998, 1998 March (Box 333)
  Small aggregate of snapshops taken by Peggy Dulaney during her trip with DR to Morocco.
- Middle East Trip, 1950s; Black-and-white images. (Box 334)
  DR trip to the Middle East, possibly to Saudi Arabia, on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. At a large event, DR met with several prominent people, possibly some heads of state.
- Ringing Point, Seal Harbor, Maine Trip, 1975, Black-and-white images. (Box 335)
  DR and PR visit to Ringing Point, their home in Seal Harbor, Maine, interspersed with some images of Manhattan. Images by Joseph Reed. They were joined in Maine by family and friends for sailing and a visit to the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden. Includes a rare image of brother Nelson's tapestry of Picasso's "Guernica" in the boathouse gallery at NAR's Seal Harbor home, Anchorage. This is one of the few known images of the interior of the boathouse gallery.
- Sweden Trip, 1971, Black-and-white images. (Box 336)
  DR trip sailing in Sweden with Swedish banker Marc Wallenberg and his family. Images by Joseph Reed.
- Luncheon in Honor of the Prime Minister of Thailand, 1968 May 7; Black-and-white images. (Box 337)
  DR trip to Thailand on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank, where he attended a luncheon in honor of Prime Minister Thanom Kittikachorn. Also attended by Eugene Black (former head of the World Bank) and Thai leaders Amnuay Viravan, Thanat Khoman, and Pote Sarasin. Images by Joseph Reed.
- Africa Trip, Part 3, 1971, Black-and-white images. (Box 338)
  DR trip to Nigeria and Ivory Coast (Cote d'Ivoire) on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. DR visited the Chase Manhattan Bank branch in Nigeria, probably in Lagos. DR met with Ado Abdullahi Bayero, emir of Kano, in Nigeria. Tours of neighborhoods, markets, and museum. DR met with Henry Konan Bedie, future president of Ivory Coast, and visited factories in the area. Boat tour and dance performances. See also Box 297 for additional images from Ivory Coast visit.
  113 images.
- Europe Trip, 1973, 1973 May; Mostly black-and-white images.; Some images are grainy. (Box 339)
  DR and PR trip to Europe on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank, including stops in England, France, and Russia. Images were taken by Joseph Reed. DR was accompanied on part of the trip by John Hugo Loudon, former CEO of Royal Dutch Shell, and Henry Ford II. He met with Edmond de Rothschild and Valery Giscard d'Estaing while in France. The Russia portion of the trip was mostly sightseeing.
  94 images.
- Middle East Trip, January 1977, 1977 Janaury; Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 340)
  DR trip to Morocco, Tunisia, Egypt, Jordan, and Israel, including a stop beforehand in Sydney, Australia. The trip was likely on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Images by Joseph Reed. In Morocco, DR met with King Hassan II during a golf game and also met with Ambassador Hadj Abdelmajid Bengelloun. Album includes images of Egyptian and Tunisian residents plus a portrait of Habib Bourguiba Jr., a Tunisian ambassdor and son of the country's first president. In Jordan, DR met with Prince Hassan bin Talal. In Israel, DR met with Teddy Kollek, mayor of Jerusalem.
- Middle East Trip, 1975, Black-and-white images. (Box 341)
  DR trip to several Middle East coutries, including Israel, Egypt, Jordan, Lebanon, Tunisia, and Algeria. Images by Joseph Reed. In Israel, DR met with Jerusalem mayor Teddy Kollek. In Egypt, he met with President Anwar Sadat. In Jordan, he met with Prince Hassan bin Talal. In Lebanon, he met with President Suleiman Frangieh. In Algeria, he met with political leader Ahmed Tewfik el Madani.
- Lincoln Center Album by Ezra Stoller, 1970; Black-and-white images. (Box 342)
  Oversized printed album of formal photographs taken by Ezra Stoller of Lincoln Center in Manhattan and the architect's planning models of the various buildings. Images of interiors, exteriors, and models. Esto Photographics retains the rights to these images.
- Album of Newspaper Clippings on David Rockefeller, 1937-1942; Album is coming apart. Clippings and pages are yellowed and faded. (Box 343)
  Ovesized album of clippings on DR's academic, early professional, and personal life as depicted in the press.
  Restricted due to preservation concerns. Album is fragile and coming apart. Permission required to access original album.
- Rabat, Morocco Trip, 1983, 1983 July (Box 344)
  DR trip to Rabat, Morocco, to meet with Prince Moulay Abdallah, who died prematurely later that year. Images by Joseph Reed of Chase Manhattan Bank.
- Birthday Gift Album, Mr. Rockefeller's 100th, 2015 June (Box 345)
  Album of DR's 100th birthday celebration with staff from the Pocantico Hills property.
- Album of DR and PR from Patricia Cisneros, 2006 February 28 (Box 346)
  Compilation album given to DR by friends Patricia and Gustavo Cisneros after an talk DR gave at the Museum of Modern Art in 2006. Images are of DR and PR with the Cisneros family at the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden in Seal Harbor, Maine, from approximately 1988.
- David and Peggy Rockefeller's Engagement Album, 1940 June; Black-and-white images. (Box 347)
  Formal album of clippings of the announcement of DR and PR's engagement in June 1940. Includes two photos of them individually.
- David and Peggy Rockefeller's Wedding Album, 1940 September 7; Black-and-white images. (Box 348)
  Formal album of clippings of DR and PR's wedding in Bedford, New York. Includes nine images of the wedding party.
- David and Peggy Rockefeller's 40th Anniversary Celebration, 1980 September; Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 349)
  Images of DR and PR's party to celebrate their 40th wedding anniversary, held at Hudson Pines, their home in Pocantico Hills, New York. Attended by family and friends.
- David Rockefeller Childhood Album, 1916-1925; Black-and-white images. (Box 350)
  Images of DR as a child. Includes his parents, his grandfather (JDR Sr.), and his siblings.